James Goh

Full-Stack Coding | Sales & Marketing | Business Intelligence | Logistics

■(801)-897-6322 ■jgoh1994@gmail.com ■ https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamesbbgoh/ ■https://github.com/jgohbb

Full stack web developer with a background in business intelligence and logistics. My strong work ethic, broad exposure and proven record in successful delivery across a variety of roles will compliment my coding skills to deliver positive value. Ready for software development position leveraging on commercial experience.

SKILLS

Javascript, JQuery, HTML, Bootstrap, JSON, API, Firebase, MySQL, MongoDB, React, GitHub, Bash, Visual Studio Code, Heroku, Laravel PHP, Express, MERN Stack.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Project: Tempic | https://jgohbb.github.io/tempic/

Technologies: Node, Express Web Server, MySql, Heroku

Description: Group project with team of four. My primary focus is on the front-end and supporting the back end to complete the project. Five images presented to the user randomly from a list of twenty possible cities. The user will need to order them from coldest to warmest with a limited number of tries. Temperatures are obtained via a weather API with information about each city provided by a wiki API.

Project: MineX | https://dallin-rodgers-minex.herokuapp.com/

Technologies: Express, Express Handlebars, Sequelize, MySql, Bcrypt, Passport, Joi

Description: Team of four with focus on back-end and authentication protocols. MineX is an online game for mining in space. When an account is created, the player is taken to their control panel where they can set out to gather ores and materials from distant asteroids to earn credits.

Project: iClicky | https://iclicky-react-game.herokuapp.com/

Technologies: React, Node

Description: Individual project. This is a memory game using React where application UI are broken into components where component states are managed and respond to user events.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rio Tinto Copper & Diamonds, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA

Commercial Executive, 2015 - 2018

- Managed the sales of precious metals and sulfuric acid with an annual sale of \$350M.
- Liaised with operations and customers, enhancing business systems, providing business solutions and analysis to improve market position and achieve strategic sales targets.
- Developed consolidated database systems for tracking and optimizing the execution of sales by linking commodity prices to contracts.

Rio Tinto Copper Group Marketing, Salt Lake City, Utah,

Senior Analyst, 2010 – 2015

- Managed team in SLC with responsibility for global and regional marketing analysis and reporting; provided market research and intelligence to the sales team and Rio Tinto groups.
- Developed corporate strategic initiatives to lower cost and grow revenue.
- Streamlined and automated marketing database which reduce redundancy by 30 percent, improve clarity and facilitate optimal sales decision-making.

Docomo Intertouch, British Columbia, Canada

Business Development Manager, 2009 – 2010

- Technology based subsidiary of telecommunications conglomerate NTT Docomo, Japan.
- Assessed and developed M&A opportunities in North America.

James Goh | page 2 of 2

Rio Tinto Copper Projects, Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada *Project Consultant.* 2008 – 2009

- Developed strategy and implementation plans to manage intellectual property;
- Designed manpower database for the greenfield Oyu Tolgoi copper project in Mongolia.

EDUCATION

University of Utah, Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp Certificate
National University of Singapore, Master of Social Sciences (Economics)
University of Western Australia, Bachelor of Economics
Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Executive Program on Supply Chain
Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Executive Program on Artificial Intelligence for Business
Strategy

CERTIFICATION

Lean–Six Sigma (Green Belt 2012) - Rio Tinto Negotiation & Influencing - ENS International (2001, 2008, 2016) Marketing Academy course – IMD International Institute UK 2012